[
  {
    "topic": "SQL",
    "subtopic": "Queries",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Which data manipulation command combines the records from one or more tables?",
    "options": ["SELECT", "JOIN", "INSERT", "UPDATE"],
    "answer": 1, 
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {  
    "topic": "SQL",
    "subtopic": "basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "SQL permits attribute names to be repeated in the same relation.",
    "options": ["TRUE", "FALSE"],
    "answer": 1,
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "SQL",
    "subtopic": "Aggregate Functions",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Which of the following is NOT an aggregate function in SQL",
    "options": ["AVG()", "COUNT()", "MAX()", "UPDATE()"],
    "answer": 3,
    "difficulty": "medium"
  },
  {
    "topic": "SQL",
    "subtopic": "basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Which of the following statements is true concerning routines and triggers?",
    "options": ["Both consist of procedural code.", "Both have to be called to operate.", "Both run automatically.", "Both are stored in the database."],
    "answer": 0, 
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "SQL",
    "subtopic": "Queries",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "A CASE SQL statement is which of the following?",
    "options": ["A way to establish an IF-THEN-ELSE in SQL.", "A way to establish a loop in SQL.", "A way to establish a data definition in SQL.", "All of the above"],
    "answer": 0, 
    "difficulty": "Medium"
  },
  {
    "topic": "SQL",
    "subtopic": "basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "The following SQL is which type of join: SELECT CUSTOMER_T. CUSTOMER_ID, ORDER_T. CUSTOMER_ID, NAME, ORDER_ID FROM CUSTOMER_T,ORDER_T WHERE CUSTOMER_T. CUSTOMER_ID = ORDER_T. CUSTOMER_ID",
    "options": ["Natural join", "Equi join", "Outer join", "Cartesian join"],
    "answer": 1, 
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "SQL",
    "subtopic": "basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Which statement is used to delete all rows in a table without having the action logged?",
    "options": ["Delete", "Remove", "Drop", "Truncate"],
    "answer": 3, 
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "SQL",
    "subtopic": "basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "The SQL statement: \n SELECT ROUND (65.726, -1) FROM DUAL;\n Prints:",
    "options": ["is illegal", "garbage", "726", "70"],
    "answer": 3, 
    "difficulty": "Medium"
  },
  {
    "topic": "SQL",
    "subtopic": "basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Which of the following operator can be used with a multiple-row subquery?",
    "options": ["=", "Between", "Not in", "<>"],
    "answer": 2, 
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
    "topic": "SQL",
    "subtopic": "Basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Which operator performs pattern matching",
    "options": ["BETWEEN", "LIKE", "EXISTS", "AS"],
    "answer": 1, 
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "SQL",
    "subtopic": "Basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "Which among the following is not type of SQL constraint",
    "options": ["PRIMARY KEY", "ALTERNATE KEY", "FOREIGN KEY", "UNIQUE"],
    "answer": 1, 
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  },
  {
    "topic": "SQL",
    "subtopic": "Basics",
    "type": "MCQ",
    "question": "What do we call the virtual table constructed from other tables in sql",
    "options": ["View", "Relation", "Procedure", "Table"],
    "answer": 0, 
    "difficulty": "Easy"
  }
]
